After loading in data and defining a model,
the next task is to define your loss and optimization functions.
For a simple classification problem like this one,
I recommend starting with cross-entropy loss and a method of gradient descent.
But you may also find it useful to read
the documentation on the various types of loss functions and optimizers.
In fact, let's check out the loss documentation.
You can see a few different types of loss here,
and we can read about cross-entropy loss.
The documentation says that the cross-entropy function is actually performing
a softmax function on an output layer and then doing negative log loss.
This means that you only need your model to produce class scores,
and then this loss function will turn those into
probabilities using a softmax function and calculate the loss,
even details how these calculations are performed.
You'll also notice that this loss is calculated
as an average value over a batch of images.
So, if a batch of 20 images is seen by our model during training,
the return loss will be the average loss over those 20 images.
Now back to our notebook,
the loss and optimization functions will really
define how the network updates its weights as it trains.
Next, we'll get to the actual training loop,
this as the number of epochs we will train for.
Epochs are how many times we want the model to
iterate through the entire training dataset.
One epoch for example means it sees every training image just once.
And I suggest starting with at least 20 epochs for this dataset.
It's good practice to start small if you're testing out
different model architectures and then increase
the number of epochs when you're trying to train your final model.
Then, we loop over each epoch and I'm going to keep track of the training loss as I go.
Inside this epoch loop is the batch loop.
Here, the train loader will load a batch of training data and we can
look at the images and the true labels for every image in that batch.
At the start of the batch loop,
we clear out any gradient calculations that PyTorch
has accumulated using optimizer.zero_grad.
Then, we call in our model and perform a forward pass.
Our model takes in the input images,
the data from our train loader and then this returns the predicted class scores,
which I'll call output.
Next, we use our defined loss function to
compare these predicted outputs and the true labels, the target.
These were again gotten from our train loader.
So, we compare a batch of outputs and target labels and calculate the cross-entropy loss.
To complete the backpropagation steps,
we then perform a backward pass to compute the gradient of
the loss and we perform a single optimization step.
This step is actually responsible for updating the values of the weights in our network.
Finally, we compute a running training loss.
This last item is a loss value that's averaged over the batch
and in this case we actually want to record the accumulated loss over the batch,
not the average quite yet.
So, I'm going to multiply it by the batch size data.size(0).
Then, after this loop has completed and we've gone through one whole epoch,
I'll calculate the average loss over that epoch.
To do this, I'm going to divide
the accumulated loss by the total number of images in our training set.
This returns an average training loss and I'll print it out after each epoch.
I should note that this is just one way to calculate the average loss.
And as you look at example code,
you may see a different calculation.
For example, you could calculate the average loss at any point in this batch loop,
as long as you add up the loss for every input image and then
divide the accumulated loss by the number of images seen by the network.
Now, after you run this training loop for some time after a number of epochs,
you'll be able to test your model on previously unseen test data.
I've provided some code that iterates through the test data from our test loader,
and applies our trained model to that data.
This code will allow you to see how well
your model performs on each class in our dataset.
Next, you'll have a chance to take a look at
this exercise code and a solution to creating an MLP for image classification.
I encourage you to look at the solution
after you've attempted to build a network of your own.