When we talk about spatial patterns in an image,
we're often talking about one of two things,
color or shape, and I want to focus on shape for a moment.
Shape can also be thought of as patterns of intensity in an image.
Intensity is a measure of light and dark, similar to brightness,
and we can often use this knowledge to detect the shape of objects in an image.
For example, say, you're trying to distinguish a person from a background in an image.
You can look at the contrast that occurs where the person ends and the background
begins to define a shape boundary that separates the two.
You can often identify the edges of an object by looking at abrupt changes in intensity,
which happen when an image changes from a very dark to light area.
In the next few videos,
you'll be using and creating specific image filters that look at
groups of pixels and detect big changes in intensity in an image.
These filters produce an output that shows various edges and shapes.
So, let's take a closer look at these filters and
see what role they play in a convolutional neural network.