Say we want to classify an input image.
There are a few ways we could go about this using a deep learning architecture.
Consider following the input layer with a sequence of convolutional layers.
This stack will discover hierarchies of spatial patterns in the image.
The first layer of filters looks at patterns in the input image,
the second looks at patterns in the previous convolutional layer, and so on.
Each of the convolutional layers requires us to specify a number of hyperparameters.
The first and second inputs to define a convolutional layer are
simply the depth of the input and the desired depth of the output.
For example, the input depth of a color image will be three for the RGB channels,
and we might want to produce 16 different filtered images in this convolutional layer.
Next, we define the size of the filters that define a convolutional layer.
These are often square and range from the size of two-by-two at the
smallest to up to a seven-by-seven or so for very large images.
Here, I'll choose to use three-by-three filters.
The stride is generally set to
one and many frameworks will have this as the default value,
so you may need to input this value.
As for padding, you may get better results if you set your padding such that
a convolutional layer will have the same width
and height as its input from the previous layer.
In the case of a three-by-three filter,
which can almost center itself perfectly on an image but misses the border pixels by one,
this padding will be equal to one.
You can read a bit more about different cases for padding below.
When deciding the depth or number of filters in a convolutional layer,
often we'll have a number of filters increase in sequence.
So, the first convolutional layer might have 16 filters.
The second second will see that depth as input and produce a layer with a depth of 32.
The third will have a depth of 64 and so on.
After each convolutional layer,
we'll apply a ReLU activation function.
If we follow this process,
we have a method for gradually increasing the depth of
our array without modifying the height and width.
The input, just like all of the layers in this sequence,
has a height and width of 32.
But the depth increases from an input layers depth of three to 16 to 32 to 64.
We call that, yes we wanted to increase the depth,
but we also wanted to decrease the height and width and discard some spatial information.
This is where max pooling layers will come in.
They generally follow every one or two convolutional layers in the sequence.
Here's one such example with a max pooling layer after each convolutional layer.
To define a max pooling layers,
you'll only need to define the filter size and stride.
The most common setting will use filters of size two with a stride of two.
This has the effect of making
the XY dimensions half of what they were from the previous layer.
In this way, the combination of convolutional and max pooling layers accomplishes
our goal of attaining an array that's quite deep but small in the X and Y dimensions.
Next, let's talk about finally connecting this output to a fully-connected layer,
and see what exactly is happening to an input as it moves through these layers.