When we design an algorithm to classify objects in images,
we have to deal with a lot of irrelevant information.
We really only want our algorithm to
determine if an object is present in the image or not.
The size of the object doesn't matter,
neither does the angle,
or if I move it all the way to the right side of the image.
It's still an image with an avocado.
In other words, we can say that we want our algorithm to
learn an invariant representation of the image.
We don't want our model to change its prediction based on the size of the object.
This is called scale invariance.
Likewise, we don't want the angle of the object to matter.
This is called rotation invariance.
If I shift the image a little to the left or to the right, well,
it's still an image with an avocado,
and this is called translation invariance.
CNN's do have some built-in translation invariance.
To see this, you'll need to first recall how we calculate max-pooling layers.
Remember that at each window location,
we took the maximum of the pixels contained in the window.
This maximum value can occur anywhere within the window.
The value of the max-pooling node would be the
same if we translated the image a little to the left,
to the right, up,
down, as long as the maximum value stays within the window.
The effect of applying many max-pooling layers in
a sequence each one following a convolutional layer,
is that we could translate the object quite far to the left,
to the top of the image,
to the bottom of the image,
and still our network will be able to make sense of it all.
This is truly a non-trivial problem.
Recall that the computer only sees a matrix of pixels.
Transforming an object's scale, rotation,
or position in the image has a huge effect on the pixel values.
We as humans can see the difference in images quite clearly,
but how do you think you'd do if you were just given the corresponding array of numbers?
Thankfully, there's a technique that works well for
making our algorithms more statistically invariant,
but it will feel a little bit like cheating.
The idea is this,
if you want your CNN to be rotation invariant,
well, then you can just add some images to your training
set created by doing random rotations on your training images.
If you want more translation invariance,
you can also just add new images created
by doing random translations of your training images.
When we do this,
we say that we have expanded the training set by augmenting the data.
Data augmentation will also help us to avoid overfitting.
This is because the model is seeing many new images.
Thus, it should be better at generalizing
and we should get better performance on the test dataset.
Let's augment the training data and the CFR 10 dataset from the previous video,
and see if we can improve our test accuracy.
We'll be using a Jupiter notebook that you can download below.