You've seen that CNN's or some of
the most powerful networks for image classification and analysis.
CNN's process visual information in a feed forward manner,
passing an input image through a collection of
image filters which extract certain features from the input image.
It turns out that these feature level representations
are not only useful for classification,
but for image construction as well.
These representations are the basis for applications like Style Transfer and Deep Dream.
Which compose images based on CNN layer activations and extracted features.
In this lesson we'll focus on learning about
and implementing the style transfer algorithm.
Style transfer allows you to apply the style of
one image to another image of your choice.
For example, here we've applied the style of Hokusai,
The Great Wave [inaudible] print to a picture of a cat.
The key to this technique is using
a trained CNN to separate the content from the style of an image.
If you can do this then you can merge the content of
one image with the style of another and create something entirely different.
Next, we'll talk about how style and content
can be separated and by the end of this lesson,
you'll have all the knowledge you need to generate a stylized image of your own design.