In the code example that I'll go through,
we'll recreate a style transfer method that's outlined in the paper,
image style transfer using convolutional neural networks.
In this paper, style transfer uses the features found in the 19 layer VGG network,
which I'll call VGG 19.
This network accepts a color image as input and
passes it through a series of convolutional and pooling layers.
Followed finally by three fully connected layers but classify the past in image.
In-between the five pooling layers,
there are stacks of two or four convolutional layers.
The depth of these layers is standard within each stack,
but increases after each pooling layer.
Here they're named by stack and their order in the stack.
Conv one, one, is the first convolutional layer
that an image is passed through in the first stack.
Conv two, one, is the first convolutional layer in the second stack.
The deepest convolutional layer in the network is conv five, four.
Now, we know that style transfer wants to create
an image that has the content of one image and the style of another.
To create this image,
which I'll call our target image,
it will first pass both the content and style images through this VGG 19 network.
First, when the network sees the content image,
it will go through the feed-forward process until it
gets to a convolutional layer that is deep in the network.
The output of this layer will be the content representation of the input image.
Next, when it sees the style image,
it will extract different features from
multiple layers that represent the style of that image.
Finally, it will use both the content and style
representations to inform the creation of the target image.
The challenge is how to create the target image.
How can we take a target image which often starts as
either a blank canvas or as a copy of our content image,
and manipulate it so that it's content is close to that of our content image,
and it's style is close to that of our style image?
Let's start by discussing in the content.
In the paper, the content representation for an image is taken as
the output from the fourth convolutional stack, conv four, two.
As we form our new target image,
we'll compare it's content representation with that of our content image.
These two representations should be close to the
same even as our target image changes it's style.
To formalize this comparison,
we'll define a content loss,
a loss that calculates the difference between
the content and target image representations,
which I'll call Cc and Tc respectively.
In this case, we calculate the mean squared difference between the two representations.
This is our content loss,
and it measures how far away these two representations are from one another.
As we try to create the best target image,
our aim will be to minimize this loss.
This is similar to how we used loss and
optimization to determine the weights of a CNN during training.
But this time, our aim is not to minimize classification error.
In fact, we're not training the CNN at all.
Rather, our goal is to change only the target image,
updating it's appearance until it's content
representation matches that of our content image.
So, we're not using the VGG 19 network in a traditional sense,
we're not training it to produce a specific output.
But we are using it as a feature extractor,
and using back propagation to minimize
a defined loss function between our target and content images.
In fact, we'll have to define a loss function between our target and style images,
in order to produce an image with our desired style.
Next, let's learn more about how to represent the style of an image.