Okay. If I look at the original paper and I scroll down close to the bottom,
I can see exactly which layers make up our style and content representations.
I see here that the content representation is taken as the output of layer conv4_2,
and the style representations are going to be made of features
from the first convolutional layer in all five stacks,
conv1_1 up to conv5_1.
Back to our notebook, I basically want to map these numbers that point
to these VGG 19 layers to their more descriptive name.
So, 0 is Conv1_1,
which is easy enough.
Next after this maxpooling layer,
I can see I have Conv2_1 at layer 5.
I'll look for the next maxpooling layer and then Conv3_1 at layer 10.
So now I want to grab Conv4_1 and Conv4_2 for our content representation.
Lastly, I also want to grab Conv5_1.
So, it might get features function,
I've listed out all the layers whose outputs I'll
need to form my style and content representations.
I find it easiest to keep all these in one list and access them by name later,
but you could also choose to separate out this content representation layer.
Okay. Great. So this completes our get features function.
Eventually, one of our tasks will be to pass a style image through
the VGG model and extract the style
features at the right layers which we've just specified.
Then, once we get these style features at a specific layer,
we'll have to compute the gram matrix.
Your next exercise will be to complete this function, gram_matrix.
This function takes in a tensor,
the output of the convolutional layer,
and returns the gram matrix,
the correlations of all the features in that layer.
So to complete this function,
you'll want to take a look at the shape of the past in tensor.
This tensor should be four-dimensional with a batch size a depth and a height and width.
You'll need to reshape this so that the height and width are flattened,
and then you can calculate the gram matrix by doing matrix multiplication.
Try this out and then I'll go through one implementation next.