So after we have our content and style features and gram matrices,
next we need to define style and content losses.
Alongside these, we need to define loss weights.
This way, we can iteratively update our target image.
First up, we're defining our style weights for each of our individual style layers.
Notice that conv4_2 is excluded here.
Now, these are just weights that are going to give one set of
style features more importance than another's.
For example, I prefer to weigh earlier layers a little bit more.
These features are often larger due to the spatial size of these feature maps.
Whereas weighting later layers might emphasize more fine-grain features.
But again, this is really a preference and up to you to customize.
I'd recommend keeping the values within the zero to one range.
Then we have are alpha and beta,
which I'm going to descriptively name our content weight and our style weight.
Earlier, we discussed this as a ratio that makes sure that style and
content are equally important in the target image creation process.
Because of how style loss is calculated,
we basically want to give our style loss a much larger weight than the content loss.
Here, it's 1 times 10 to the 6th and content loss is just one.
Now, if beta is too large,
you may see too much of a stylized effect,
but these values are good starting points.
Next, we enter the iteration loop,
and here's where you're actually going to be changing your target image.
Now, this is not a training process,
so it's arbitrary where you stop updating the target image.
I'd recommend at least 2,000 iterations,
but you may want to do more or less depending on
your computing resources and desired effect.
So, in this iteration loop,
I'm going to ask you to calculate the content loss first.
This will just be the mean square difference between
the target and content representations.
I've given you some example code up here.
We can get those representations by getting the features from our target image,
and then comparing those features at a particular layer,
in this case conv4_2,
to the features at that layer for our content image.
We're going to subtract these two representations and
then square that difference and calculate the mean.
This will give us our content loss.
Next in this loop, you're going to do something similar for the style loss.
Only this time, you have to go through
multiple layers for our multiple representations for style.
Recall that each of our relevant layers was listed in our style_weights dictionary above.
Here, I'm assuming you've calculated our target features so
you can access a single target feature by layer.
You'll get some style features from
the target image and calculate the gram matrix for that layer.
Then you have to compare with this style_gram for the style image at
that layer weighting it with our specified style weight for this layer.
Here, these are going to be added up and
normalized by the number of values in that layer.
Finally, you should be able to add up everything and calculate a total loss.
This is what will be used to update the target image using typical back propagation.
So, try out completing this loss code on your own.
This is the last piece of code you'll need to implement style transfer.
Then, you'll be able to test this method on target images of your own design.