All right, here's my final solution.
I played around with the values for style_weights giving more weight to earlier layers.
I left the content and style_weights at one and one times 10_6.
Then I got into the iteration loop.
I first got a list of target features using our get_features function.
Then I defined our content loss by looking at the target_features at
the layer conv4_2 and the content_features at conv4_2.
So, I'm comparing my content image and my target image content representations.
I found the distance between the two and calculated the mean squared difference.
Then the style_loss. For this one,
I looked at every layer in our style_weights dictionary.
For each of these layers,
I got the target_feature at that layer.
For example, this would be what happens if our target image goes
through our VGG 19 Network and hits conv1_1.
The output of the convolutional layer is then fed into our gram_matrix function.
This gives us our target gram_matrix.
Earlier, I calculated a dictionary of gram matrices for our style image.
So, I get the gram_matrix for our style image by accessing that by layer.
Then here, I'm calculating the mean squared difference
between our style_gram and target_gram matrix.
Again, this is for a particular layer and I weighted
by the weights that I specified in our style_weights dictionary.
So, for example, for the first layer conv1_1,
I'm going to multiply the difference between the target and style_gram matrices by one.
Then I'm adding that layer style_loss to
our accumulated style_loss and just dividing it by the size of that layer.
This effectively normalizes our layer style_loss.
So, by the end of this for loop,
I have the value for this style_loss at all five of my convolutional layers added up.
Finally, I can compute the total_loss,
which is just my content_loss and style_loss
summed up and multiplied by their respective weights.
Our content_loss is multiplied by one and style is
multiplied by one times 10_6, and that's basically it.
I run this loop for 2,000 iterations,
but I showed intermittently images every 400.
I printed out the loss,
which was quite large,
and I could see a difference in my octopus image right away.
Then at the end of my 2,000 iterations,
I displayed my content and my target image side-by-side.
You can see that the target image still looks a lot like an octopus.
In fact, I think I could have stylized this even more.
But it also has the colors and
some brushstroke texture from the Hockney painting that I used as a style image.
Now, using this notebook,
you should be able to choose any content and style image combo that you want.
Some example images have been provided in this notebook folder for you,
but if you run this in a local environment,
you can combine any images.
If you do end up making your own images,
I'd encourage you to share it on social media.
I know that I would love to see it.