Is there a story you have for an error or some feature that,
it was like a bug that was found early on?
Yeah. This was before public release.
I think we were in- so,
public release was 0.1.12 and I think this was
like 0.1.6 or something - Something really early - and Justin Johnson,
who was interning at a fair,
who's a student at Stanford, also runs-
Yes, I think I've seen some of his computer vision videos.
Yeah. So, he co-runs the CS231n course on ConvNets at Stanford.
So, he was doing his research and then he was like,
"My networks aren't training,
and I started investigating.
It turns out if you have a non-contiguous tensor and send it through a linear layer,
it'll just give you garbage really."
Just garbage.
And we were like,
"Oh man, that just sounds bad."
So, we had pretty robust unit testing,
but we forgot to add non-contiguous checks to all of our unit tests.
So, that was a particularly fun one.
Yeah, that's a big bug.
That's good though that someone notices it before going fully public.
One of the reasons why I like PyTorch is,
especially for our teaching,
it just merges so nicely with Python,
which a lot of our students already know and it's something that's
like fairly intuitive to pick up as a programming language.
But I think about Python and I also think
there's a trade off there where
the readability comes at a cost of it being a little bit slow.
So, maybe you could talk a bit about that decision.
Sure. Initially, when we wrote PyTorch,
the autograd and- the entire internal autograd engine is all written in Python.
Then, one of our aims for PyTorch was that it should be very imperative,
very usable, very Pythonic,
but at the same time as fast as any other framework out there.
So, we put special focus on that.
One of the consequences of that was large parts of PyTorch live in C++,
except whatever is user facing is still in Python,
so that you can attach your debugger, you can print.
All of those are still very hackable.
But, yeah, it gives you the best of both worlds where
the main parts that the userland would need to know are in Python,
but of the critical parts that are internals,
they're all in C++.
Okay. That makes sense.