So, recently, PyTorch has become pretty popular in
the research community and I'm wondering if you think you know like why that is.
True. I think it's again going back to how we built and traded on PyTorch.
We gave it to a bunch of researchers and we took
a rapid feedback from them and improve the product before it became mature.
So, the core design of PyTorch is very,
very researcher friendly by doing
this reinforcement loop with researchers as we developed it.
I think that is the main reason.
It's very easy to do debugging.
It's very Pythonic.
If you know any of the popular Python machine learning or data science packages,
it feels very natural that,
the RBI looks very like numpy.
So, I think that's the main thing that's been pulling researchers to PyTorch.
Yeah. So, it sounds like PyTorch is designed with users and just their feedback in mind.
I think some other libraries that makes me think of like sometimes they're designed with
scalability and production needs first rather than users and ease of use.
So, I'm wondering if you could talk a bit about how PyTorch,
especially in its latest version,
does also add features that make it easier to deploy models to production.
Sure. So, I think the fundamental concept that if you want to build a usable library,
it is intention that production is I think not correct.
What happens is people from day one,
if they put a focus on production,
they don't need to make the library usable as well as,
which means that it becomes like fairly inflexible or like unusable.
So, with PyTorch 1.0,
something that we did was we said you researchers,
you want to do imperative code,
all of that is great.
It all works out very well.
But if you want, unlike the code,
PyTorch 0.4, it scaled up to hundreds of GPUs of pilot training.
What we mean by production is you want
to export your whole model and do like a C plus plus
runtime or you want to run things like you'd
take your network and quantize it and start running into the 32-bit,
you want to run it at eight bits or four bytes.
That kind of stuff,
what we built PyTorch or when we could schedule
for production is you do your research but when you want it to be production ready,
you just add function annotations to
your model which are like these one-liners that are top of a function.
Then, PyTorch will parse your model,
your Python program itself,
and then make it into our own internal format that can be shipped to production.
So, its kind of converting all of your Python code into,
is it C plus plus code or just sort of an intermediate representation?
It's an intermediate representation that can be run in C plus plus.
We provide an interpreter,
the C plus plus only.
But anyone can take that IR,
which is called intermediate representation and then they can run it
in their own virtual machine that they've built for themselves.
That's great. I mean, it kind of makes me think of,
if someone writes a Word document or something and pages and you just export
it to PDF and then if you have is like you can send it anywhere and anyone can read it.
Exactly.
So, when you are moving in between say like
a model you've written in PyTorch and Python and an intermediate representation.
See there is a bug in there,
what will happen if you try to
debug with intermediate representation or is that something you don't ever want to do?
So, you don't ever have to do that.
So, what happens is you're building your model,
you add your function annotation as an,
it's just optional, it's there,
but you can disable it whenever you want.
Either you can comment out the function annotation or you can have
a global variable that says like switch off all compilation.
So, it's like 90 percent of the time when you're doing experimentation and research,
you're adjusting your irregular patronage mode.
But then when you decide "This model is super solid,
I've like very trustworthy of this thing.
It's been around for a while.
I want to ship it to production."
You add function annotations and it becomes
this magical black box that you don't usually need to touch.
But if you, again, want to experiment with it,
you just remove the annotations.
Okay. So, experimentation, prototyping and the Python and PyTorch that we know and love.
Then, once everything's look good to go,
you can export it using annotations.