That's really interesting that you can do it piece by piece as well.
At Udacity, we use a lot of Jupyter Notebooks to sort of break up tasks
as far as like defining a model and training it,
and I think it's really valuable to look at things
like one pea at a time as these building blocks.
Yeah. Absolutely. The other part that I think is worth telling is,
if you have a giant model,
you might not want to change big parts of the model.
So, lets say there is a ResNet block.
You might want to change how the ResNet
looks and everything but the blocks in the ResNet,
you almost never generally change.
Like, they're just processing input data in the same kind of way.
Yeah. Exactly, there like an LSTM cell.
LSTM cell is a standard definition cell.
You might change how the LSTM is put together and how many layers there are and stuff,
but the cell as the core of it you never usually change.
So, you can just add functional annotations
to these smaller components while training the other components a lot.
Which is why we call the new programming model hybrid front end,
because you can make parts of a model compiled,
parts of model still experimenting,
and then that just gives you the best of both worlds.
Yeah. So, this hybrid front end is allowing you
to just sort of switch in between Python and basically like a C++ representation?
Yeah.
That's really interesting.
So, if I was building a model and I wanted to- is there a way that I could sort of use
optimization to train it faster or is it strictly these annotations
are used strictly for after a model is trained?
So, all of this is powered by what we call the JIT compiler in PyTorch.
So, the [inaudible] digit compiler,
in the short-term is to make sure we can export everything to production ready.
Because we asked our users what's the thing that's most missing
in PyTorch that's holding you back.
They said, we use it at all these companies,
like I've worked at my startup or I work at
my big tech company and constantly other people around me are like,
you can use PyTorch but remember you can't ship it to production.
So, we wanted to first focus and remove that big constraint,
make our users happy, open up that market.
But the long-term investment of the JIT compiler remained to,
is the parts of the model they're compiled,
we're going to make them non-trivially faster by fusing operations,
making more of the memory bandwidth bound operations into compute bond operations,
and as newer hardwares come through,
we can apply special tricks that are particular to
each hardware that can do various things when they see a larger graph.
Like make it more memory efficient and things like that.
Yeah.
But that's the longer term plan,
to not just leveraged this JIT compiler we're using for exporting a train model,
but also while you're training to make sure things get faster.
So, before PyTorch 1.0,
what were some of the process for moving a model to deployment?
about six to nine months ago we introduced an open standard called ONNX, O-N-N-X,
and it's a standard that is not even like just focusing on PyTorch,
it was a standard we tried to develop
where all deep learning frameworks can talk to each other.
That's another formatting kind of stuff. Yeah.
That is correct. We partnered with Microsoft,
with various big players to make
sure all the deep learning frameworks like Chainer,
Caffe 2, PyTorch and TensorFlow,
someone can take a model that's trained in one and then export it to another framework.
So, with PyTorch, the model then before 1.0,
was to only export it to ONNX and then run it as another framework like TensorFlow.
I see.
The shortcomings of that which we felt were that ONNX is a standard,
which means that all PyTorch models
couldn't be exported because the standard hasn't developed fast enough to cover that.
So, which means it was turning at models that are more complicated,
wouldn't be ONNX exportable.
Which is why we talk like we want a robust solution,
and that's the 1.0 story.
That's great. So, it's so instead of these separate steps
of exporting and then importing into a different framework,
you have kind of like squished all these steps into
one thing that you can do an a hybrid front end.
Exactly.
That does sound ideal.