When you talk about the pace of research and thinking about deploying models,
are there projects that you find really exciting,
that are happening in PyTorch uniquely or not uniquely?
There are a lot of products I'm interested in,
just because they're very crazy ideas.
Those are my favorite as well.
Yeah. So, there was this one paper written by one person,
Andrew Brock and it's called SMASH,
where one neural network would generate
the weights that would be powered by for another neural network.
Okay.
So, it was like this neural network architects of search except that
it's you're exploring all possible neural network architectures
at once because the first neural network is generating the architecture and
the weights for your neural network.
That is the final neural network.
I see.
It is very funky.
It took me a long time to even figure out like how he managed to do it in code.
It was always in PyTorch and it looked very like, oh my god.
It's like you give someone a calculator and they make Mario Kart out of it.
Yeah or like a calculator programs another calculator or something.
Yeah. So, there are several other examples.
There's the [inaudible] from Facebook that have been closely following.
It was more of a text-to-text processing model.
So, you give some text and then it would generate another text.
Initially, it was used for machine translation and
all the standard language modeling, that kind of stuff.
But more recently, some of the researchers Angela Fan and her collaborators,
they published what you call hierarchical story generation.
So, you would seed a story that like,
"Hey, I want a story of a boy swimming in a pond."
Then it would actually like generate a story.
That's interesting.
Of the dead flood.
Yeah. A character like a vague situation.
I find that very fun and interesting.
That is that is also,
I think text analysis can be really interesting when it comes to like,
how do you actually like formalize ideas of
understanding the context of something or where it might be going in the future.
I think that's pretty good. I think too,
when I look at research and some of my favorite papers are paired
with like openly available GitHub repositories of work.
We actually have someone [inaudible] who was doing the cycle again of formulation and his code is
publicly available on GitHub and implemented in PyTorch and it's
also just like very readable where you look at something you can clearly see like,
here are the inputs, here is what's happening in as far as it being transformed,
and here are the desired outputs.
I think that's something that I really like to see and it's
something that I see more with PyTorch than other languages.