Then I kind of have two sort of last questions for you, like big picture.
Like if you think about maybe just a year from now,
so I'm not like thinking too far for this tooling,
where would you want to see
like PyTorch being used or where would you want that community to sort of be?
Yeah. So, I've been thinking about this pretty hard.
I mean we have all these awesome community.
If you see people who use pi torch,
they publish in ICLR, in NIPS,
in ICML, CVPR all of these like top tier conferences.
We got the deep learning crowd
especially in research and startups maybe not the United Airlines.
Right.
We got these people.
Next thing I was thinking was,
deep learning itself is becoming
a very pervasive and essential competent and many other fields.
If you look at health care plus data that sub-field.
Or you look at computational chemistry,
you take what CERN does,
you know, particle physics.
All of these areas like you take like a Neurobiology,
Neuroscience, they're all starting.
If you carefully look,
they're all starting to use deep learning.
The way they use it,
is it's a very,
very rudimentary- for them it's like oh look there's this GitHub repo
that shows us how to put in our like our brain scans,
and then get out segmented version.
It's like some unit implementation somewhere.
I think more- empowering them more
by lowering- their main problem is they didn't know deep learning.
So, my thinking is,
maybe we should just go into these fields and build them
packages that are- that lower their barrier of entry to use deep learning.
So, there's like 10 research labs they
use neuroscience who do neuroscience who want to use deep learning capabilities,
just go understand what they actually need,
and then build a cute package which they can relate to.
When we say a PyTorch is pythonic,
Python people who use use Python can relate to it, right?
Yeah.
I want PyTorch to be neurosciencic and particle physicic.
So, I'm just making sure that those communities are
empowered and not just like poking holes randomly.
Yeah. Yeah, I like the idea of linear,
going to ask people what they need as far as like kind of a data analysis tool.
Yeah.