And then my last question for you is if you have any advice for people
who are just sort of getting into the field of AI and deep learning,
and curious to learn more.
If you have any recommendations for them.
Sure. I would just say,
be hands-on from day one.
I think I spent a long time trying
to collect all the material that is possibly available,
I think get a 100 textbooks because it seemed like if I just got the textbooks,
I already got the knowledge in some fractional form.
And then like also just do a lot of passive stuff,
like listening to an android lecture or reading some blog post,
and then be like, "Oh, oh, yeah.
Those types, those types."
Then there's always the barrier which is,
when you actually sat and try to do something, you'd just black out.
"I know all of this stuff.
I read all of it, why I can't apply it?"
I think that details as students are trying to get into the field of deep learning,
either to apply it to their own stuff or just to learn the concepts,
it's very important to make sure you do it from day one.
Yeah.
Stay on track. [inaudible] you encourage people to do projects,
and review the projects,
and give people feedback.
I think that's a very very good interaction,
that's my only advice to people.
It's to make sure you do lesser,
but do it hands-on,
rather than do a lot more,
but then just glance over it.
Yeah. That's a sort of in-depth exploratory approach,
almost doing like a full circle back to just really
being consuming the information you need,
but then really being curious and exploratory on your own design.
Well, cool. Well, thank you so much for joining us.
And I'm excited to try out PyTorch [inaudible].
Absolutely. Thank you.