CNNs achieve state of the art results in
a variety of problem areas including Voice User Interfaces,
Natural Language Processing, and computer vision.
In the field of Voice User Interfaces,
Google made use of CNNs in
its recently released WaveNet model which we've linked to below.
WaveNet takes any piece of text as input and does
an excellent job of returning computer-generated audio of a human reading the text.
What's really cool is that if you supply the algorithm with enough samples of your voice,
it's possible to train it to sound just like you.
As for the field of Natural Language Processing,
you'll see later that Recurrent Neural Networks are
used more frequently than Convolutional Neural Networks.
CNNs, however, can be used in this area too.
We provide a link below that shows you how
CNNs are used to extract information from sentences.
This information can be used to classify sentiment.
For example, is the writer happy or sad?
If they're talking about a movie,
did they like or dislike it?
In this program, we'll focus on applications and computer vision and
specifically work towards applying CNNs to image classification tasks.
Given an image, your CNN will assign
a corresponding label which you believe summarizes the content of the image.
This is a core problem in computer vision and
has applications in a wide range of problem areas.
For instance, CNNs are used to teach
artificially intelligent agents to play video games such as Atari Breakout.
The CNN-based models are able to learn to play
games without being given any prior knowledge of what a ball is.
And without even being told precisely what the controls do,
the agent only sees the screen and
its score but it does have access to all of the controls that you'd give a human user.
With this limited knowledge,
CNNs can extract crucial information that allows them to develop a useful strategy.
CNNs have even been trained to play Pictionary.
There's currently an app called Quickdraw that
guesses what you're drawing based on your finger-drawn picture.
The applications of CNNs are almost limitless.
Go, for example, is
an ancient Chinese board game considered one of the most complex games in existence.
It said that there are more configurations
in the game than there are atoms in the universe.
Recently, researchers from Google's DeepMind use CNNs to train
an artificially intelligent agent to beat human professional Go players.
CNNs also allowed drones to navigate unfamiliar territory.
Drones are now used to deliver medical supplies to remote areas.
And CNNs give the drone the ability to
see or to determine what's happening in streaming video data.
But for now we'll consider algorithms that can decode images of text.
Maybe you'd like to digitize the historical book or your handwritten notes,
then you could start with developing an algorithm that can
identify images of letters or numbers or punctuation.
Similarly, you could develop an algorithm to
aid self-driving cars with reading road signs.
Likewise, Google has built a better more accurate street maps of the world
by training an algorithm that can read house numbers signs from street view images.
CNNs achieved state of the art performance in all of these problem domains.
We mentioned that while it's possible to use
the neural network from the previous section for image classification,
you can almost always,
if not always, get better results with the CNN.
In the next few videos,
we will explore why this is the case.