I'll be teaching this lesson in tandem with Alexis.
And as she already mentioned this lesson is all about
convolutional neural networks and how they improve our ability to classify images.
In general, CNNs can look at images as a whole and learn to
identify spatial patterns such as prominent colors and shapes,
or whether a texture is fuzzy or smooth and so on.
The shapes and colors that define any image and
any object in an image are often called features.
I'll cover how a CNN can learn to identify
these features and how a CNN can be used for image classification.
And Alexis will talk about the various layers that
make up a complete convolutional neural network.
By the end of this lesson,
you should have all the skills you need to
define and train an image classifier of your own.