Let's begin by investigating how deep learning can
be used to recognize a single object in an image.
In this example, we want to design
an image classifier that takes in an image of a hand-written number,
and produces a predicted class for that number.
This class ideally, correctly identifies the given image.
To build this, we'll use the MNIST database,
which contains thousands of small gray scale images of hand-written digits.
Each image depicts one of the numbers zero through nine.
This database is perhaps one of
the most famous databases in the field of machine and deep learning.
It was one of the first databases used to prove the usefulness of
neural networks and has continued to inform
the development of new architectures overtime.
If you look over this small sample of data,
you might notice that some digits are more legible than others.
For instance, if you squint just right,
this three could pass for an eight.
You can imagine that the dataset contains some fours that could pass for nines,
or ones and sevens.
Even with these subtleties,
for us the task of identifying these numbers is pretty easy.
We also want to design an appropriate model such that
it too can accurately distinguish between each of these numbers.
Using deep learning, we can take a data-driven approach to training an algorithm
that can examine these images and discover
patterns that distinguish one number from another.
Our algorithm will need to attain some level of
understanding of what makes a hand-drawn one look like a one,
and how images of ones differ from images of say twos or threes.
The first step in recognizing patterns in
images is learning how images are seen by computers.
So, before we start to design an algorithm,
let's first visualize this data and take a closer look at these images.