When I type in mlp for mnist into Google,
a few things pop up,
including a couple of code implementations.
This first one from the official keras GitHub repository looks like a reputable source.
Scrolling through this code,
I can see that they've imported the MNIST dataset and that they
flattened each input image into a vector of size 784.
Here, it looks like they're using one hidden layer to convert that input to be 512 nodes.
We can also see an activation function being applied,
a relu function, and we have one more hidden layer also with 512 nodes.
We can also see some Dropout layers in between.
This 0.2 means they have a 20 percent probability of
Dropout or of a node being turned off during a training cycle.
As you've learned, Dropout layers are used to avoid overfitting data.
Lastly, I see one more fully connected layer that's
producing an output vector of length 10 for a number of classes.
When I look at a source like this,
I first try to think about whether it makes sense.
I know that the more hidden layers I include in the network,
the more complex patterns this network will be able to detect,
but I don't want to add unnecessary complexity either.
My intuition is telling me that for small images,
two hidden layers sounds very reasonable.
Now, this is just one solution to the task of handwritten digit classification.
The next step in approaching a problem like this is to either, one,
keep looking and see if you can find another structure that appeals to you; then two,
when you do find a model or two that look interesting,
try them out in code and see how well they perform.
This model that I found is good enough for me,
so I think I'm going to proceed with defining
an MLP with two hidden layers based on this structure.