Now that we've decided on the structure of our MLP,
let's talk a bit about how this entire thing will actually learn from the MS data.
What happens when it actually sees an input image.
Take this input image of a two for instance.
Say we feed this image into the network and when we do so,
we get these ten class scores for my output layer.
Again, a higher score means that the network is more
certain that the input image is of that particular class.
Four is the largest value here and negative two is the smallest.
So, the network believes that the image input is least likely
to be a 103 and most likely to be an eight,
but this is incorrect.
We can see that the correct label is two.
So, what we can do is tell our network to learn from this mistake.
As a network trains, we measure any mistakes that it makes using a loss function,
whose job is to measure the difference between the predicted and true class labels.
Then using back propagation,
we can compute the gradient of the loss with respect to the models' weights.
In this way, we quantify how bad a particular weight
is and find out which weights in the network are responsible for any errors.
Finally, using that calculation,
we can choose an optimization function like
gradient descent to give us a way to calculate a better weight value.
Towards this goal, the first thing we'll need to do
is make this output layer a bit more interpretable.
What's commonly done is to apply
a softtmax activation function to convert these scores into probabilities.
To apply a softmax function to this output layer,
we begin by evaluating the exponential function at each of the scores,
then we add up all of the values.
Let's denote this sum with a capital "S".
Then we divide each of these values by the sum.
When you plug in all of the math,
you get these 10 values.
Now each value yields the probability that
the image depicts its corresponding image class.
For instance, the network believes that the image shows an
eight with 44.1 percent probability.
Remember that the input to the network was
an image of a handwritten two and yet the network
incorrectly predicts that the image shows a two with only 16.2 percent probability.
Now our goal is to update the weights of the network in response to this mistake,
so that next time it sees this image,
it predicts that two is the most likely label.
In a perfect world, the network would predict that
the image is 100 percent likely to be the true class.
In order to get the model's prediction closer to the ground truth,
we'll need to define some measure of exactly how far
off the model currently is from perfection.
We can use a loss function to find any errors between
the true image classes and our predicted classes,
then backpropagation will find out
which model parameters are responsible for those errors.
Since we're constructing a multi-class classifier,
we'll use categorical cross entropy loss.
To calculate the loss in this example,
we begin by looking at
the model's predicted probability of the true class which is 16.2 percent.
Cross entropy loss looks at this probability value which in
decimal form is 0.162 and takes the negative log loss of that value.
In this case, we get negative log 0.162 or 1.82.
Now for argument's sake,
say instead that the weights of the network were slightly different.
The model instead returned at these predicted probabilities.
This prediction is much better than the one
above and when we calculate the cross entropy loss,
we get a much smaller value.
In general, it's possible to show that the categorical cross entropy loss is defined in
such a way that the loss is lower when
the model's prediction agrees more with the true class label,
and it's higher when the prediction and the true class label disagree.
As a model trains, its goal will be to find the weights that minimize
this loss function and therefore give us the most accurate predictions.
So, a loss function and backpropagation give us
a way to quantify how bad a particular network weight is,
based on how close a predicted and the true class label are from one another.
Next, we need a way to calculate a better weight value.
In the previous lesson, you were encouraged to think of
the loss function as a surface that resembles a mountain range.
Then to minimize this function,
we need only find a way to descend to the lowest value.
This is the role of an optimizer.
The standard method for minimizing the loss and optimizing
for the best weight values is called "Gradient Descent".
You've been introduced to a number of ways to perform
gradient descent and each method has a corresponding optimizer.
The surface depicted here is an example of a loss function
and all of the optimizers are racing towards the minimum of the function.
As you can see, some do better than others and you're
encouraged to experiment with all of them in your code.