You've learned a lot about how to approach the task of image classification.
In this notebook, I'll go over how to load in image data,
define a model, and train it.
You may already be familiar with this process from
the earlier lesson on deep learning with PyTorch,
but I'd encourage you to stay tuned just so you can see another example in detail.
I'll present this code as an exercise.
Then you'll get a chance to change this code,
define your own model,
and try it out on your own in a Jupyter Notebook, much like this one.
So, the first thing I've done in this notebook is to
load in the necessary torch and NumPy libraries.
Next, I'm going to import the torchvision datasets and transformation libraries.
I'll use these to actually load in
the MNIST dataset and transform it into a Tensor datatype.
Here transforms.ToTensor is where I define that transformation.
The tensor datatype is just a data type that's very similar to a NumPy array,
only it can be moved onto a GPU for
faster calculation, which you'll learn more about later.
You'll also see that I've set some parameters for loading in the image data.
I can define the batch size which is the number of
training images that will be seen in one training iteration,
where one training iteration means one time that a network
make some mistakes and learn from them using back propagation.
The number of workers is if you want to load data in parallel.
For most cases, zero will work fine here.
Now I'm going to load in training and test data using datasets.MNIST.
I'm going to download each set and I'm going to
transform it into a tensor datatype which I defined here.
I'll put the downloaded data into a directory named data.
Finally, I'm going to create training and test loaders.
These loaders taking our data that we defined above,
our batch size and number of workers.
The train and test loaders give
us a way to iterate through this data one batch at a time.
Downloading the data may take a minute or two.
After I've downloaded my data,
I do the first step in any image analysis task,
I visualize the data.
Here I'm grabbing one batch of images and
their correct labels and I'm plotting 20 of them.
Here you can see a variety of MNIST images and their labels.
This step allows me to check and make sure that
these images look how I expect them to look.
I can even look at an image in more detail.
Here I'm just looking at one image in our set and I'm displaying the gray scale values.
You can see that these values are normalized
and the brightest pixels are close to a value of one.
The black pixels have a value of zero.
Next comes the really interesting part which is defining the MLP model.
We've talked about defining the input hidden and output layers
and so I'll leave most of this section for you to fill out.
I do want to point out a couple of things here.
First the init function.
To define any neural network in PyTorch you have to define and
name any layers that have learned weight values in the Init function,
in this case, any fully-connected linear layers that you define.
I've defined a sample first input layer which I've named FC1 for you.
This has 784 or 28 by 28 inputs and a number of hidden nodes.
This is the number of outputs that this layer will produce.
For now, I've left this as one and this will have
to be changed to create a working solution.
Next, you have to define the feedforward behavior of your network.
This is just how an input X will be passed through various layers and transformed.
I'm assuming the past in X will be a grayscale image like
an MNIST image and I've provided some starting code in here for you.
First, I've made sure to flatten the input image X by using the view function.
View takes in a number of rows and columns and
then squishes and input into that desired shape.
In this case, the number of columns will be 28 by
28 or 784 and by putting a negative one here,
this function will automatically fit all of the x values into this column shape.
The end result is that this X will be a vector of 784 values.
Then I'm passing this flattened vector to
our first fully-connected layer defined up here.
I just call this layer by name,
pass in our input and apply a relu activation function.
A relu should be applied generally to
the output of every hidden layer so that those outputs
are consistent positive values and finally I return the transformed X.
Now to complete this model,
you should add to the init end forward functions so that
the final returned X is a list of class scores.
Next, I'm going to describe how you might go about training
your defined model and complete this task on your own.