I'm going to quickly show you how I went about
defining and training an MLP for image classification.
So first, I just loaded in and looked at my normalized image data.
Then, I started to define the classification model.
I started with the fully connected layer FC1 that sees
the 784 entry long vector that represents a flattened image as input.
Then, I proceed it based on the resource that I found,
which had two hidden layers with 512 inputs and outputs.
I've actually stored those values here as two variables, hidden_1 and hidden_2.
This is an extra step, but it makes it easy should I want to change
these values later on for testing or something else.
So, to complete my first fully connected layer,
I put hidden_1 as the number of outputs I want this to produce.
Then, I create a second fully connected layer, FC2,
which takes in that number of outputs and produces 512 outputs again.
I also want to be clear that the outputs of one layer feed into the inputs of the next.
Then, I've defined the last fully connected layer FC3,
such that it sees 512 inputs and produces 10 outputs.
The 10 outputs correspond to the number of digit classes zero through nine.
So, this layer will produce our class scores.
Finally, still in the init function,
I've also defined a dropout layer with a dropout probability of 0.2 or 205.
Now that I've defined all the layers that I need to make up this classification MLP,
I have to explicitly define the feedforward behavior of the network.
With the forward function,
I basically want to answer how will an input vector proceed through these layers?
So, the input x starts out as a 28 by 28 image tensor,
and my first step is to flatten it into a 784-length vector.
Once the input is flattened,
I'm passing it through the first fully connected layer,
FC1, and applying an activation function.
Next, I'm going to do the exact same thing with our second fully connected layer, FC2.
Only in-between these two layers,
I'm actually adding a dropout layer which would help prevent over-fitting.
After x passes through our second hidden layer,
we're going to add one more dropout layer and reach our final fully connected layer.
You'll notice that I'm not applying an activation function to this final layer.
That's because later it will have a softmax activation function applied to it.
So right now, I am leaving it as is and returning the final transformed x.
Because FC3 produces 10 outputs,
this x should represent our 10 class scores.
Okay. Then, I'm instantiating and printing
out the net to make sure it has the layers that I want.
I should see our three linear layers and our dropout.
The next step is defining the loss and optimization functions.
Here, I'm defining the last criterion as cross-entropy loss.
This is just a pretty standard loss for any classification task.
Then, I'm going to use stochastic gradient descent,
SGD, from the torch optimization library.
This takes in our model parameters and a learning rate.
I've set a learning rate of 0.01.
If you find that your loss is decreasing too slowly or sporadically,
you can change this value.
Next, I spent some time training this model for 50 epochs.
This took some time because I'm just using my CPU for now,
and later I'll show you how to use a GPU for faster training.
At the end of each of these epochs I printed out
the training loss and watched how it decreased over time.
You can see that it decreased fairly quickly at first and then later
on slows down especially around the 40 epoch mark.
But it is still decreasing up to epoch 50.
Then, to actually see how well my trained model generalizes to new data,
I tested on our test data that we loaded in at the start.
Here, I've iterated through all the data in our test litter.
I applied the model and recorded the test loss.
Recall that our model is actually returning a list of class scores.
To isolate our predicted class,
I'm going to take the maximum value of the scores and return it as our prediction.
Then, I compare this prediction to our target label.
This creates a list whether a certain prediction was correct or not,
then I actually separate these into the 10 classes
and I print out the accuracy for each class.
I have our overall test loss and our overall accuracy which is 97%.
This is pretty good, and you can see among
all the digit classes this value is pretty consistent.
The model seems to do the worst on images of the number seven or eight.
But an even distribution indicates that your model
is trained pretty evenly on each type of data.
I've also included a cell,
where you can display test images and the predicted and true labels side-by-side.
This makes it easy to see if you've gotten any specific image wrong.
But going back up to the test accuracy overall,
I actually wonder if I could do even better.
If I could improve this model by adding, say,
another layer to find more patterns in the data.
I even wonder if I chose the right point to stop training this model.
In fact, one thing to note is that I stopped training at
50 epochs based on only how I expected the loss to decrease over time.
But it's more of an art than a science at this point.
So next, I'll talk about one more concrete method of knowing when to stop training.
A technique called model validation.