So, in our last example,
I got pretty good classification accuracy just by looking at how during
training the cross entropy loss that
measured the difference between predicted and true classes,
got smaller and smaller.
I estimated when a good time to stop training would be,
when the training loss had plateaued it's decreasing.
But as you just learned,
there's a way to use a validation dataset to programmatically know when to stop training.
So, I'm going to show you how to add that encode.
So, the first thing I'm going to do,
is to create a validation dataset much like we created training and test sets.
In fact, I'm actually going to take a percentage of data from the training set.
I'll set a variable valid size to take 20 percent of
the training set data and turn it into validation data.
There should be a good enough size since the MNIST dataset is very large.
Then I'm going to use something called,
subset random sampler to help me do the work of splitting the training data.
First, I'll record how many training images there are,
and I'll determine which indices in the training set I'll
access to create both sets training and validation.
I'll list out all the possible indices by grabbing the length of the entire training set.
So, these indices are going to be the values that point to
each of the 70,000 images in the training set.
Then, I'm going to shuffle these indices so that any index I select out of this list,
will reference a random piece of data.
Then, I'm defining a split boundary,
and this is just going to be the number of examples
that I want to include in the validation set.
So, it's going to be 20 percent of our training data.
Then I'll use this to get an 80-20 split between training and validation data.
Finally, I'm using subset random sampler to
create data samplers for this training and validation data.
This adds one more argument to our train loader and validation loaders.
So, previously, I had only training and test data loaders,
and now I've split the training data into two sets by essentially shuffling it and
selecting 20 percent for validation set using a specific data sampler.
So, now, we officially have a validation set loader
and I'm going to scroll down to my training loop to actually use this validation set.
Okay. Here's our training loop and this time
in addition to keeping track of the training loss,
I'm also going to track the validation loss.
I'll actually want to start training whenever I reach an epic for
which the training loss decreases but the validation loss does not.
So, I'm going to track the change in the validation loss,
and specifically, I'll track the minimum validation loss over time,
so that I can compare it to the current validation loss and
see if it's increased or decreased from the minimum over a given epic.
So, within our epic loop,
we have our usual training batch loop and we also have a validation batch loop.
This is looping through all the data and labels in the validation set.
It's applying our model to that data and recording the loss as usual.
Notice, we're not performing the back propagation step here.
That is reserved only for our training data.
Then, I've added a little bit to my print statement and I'm
printing out the average validation loss after each epic as well.
Also at the end of each epic,
I'm going to check the validation loss and
see if it's less than the currently recorded minimum.
If it is, I'm going to save the model because that
means the validation loss has decreased,
and I'll store that as the new minimum value.
You may have noticed that I set the initial minimum to infinity.
This high-value guarantees that this loss will update after the first epic.
Also take note of this line which allows me to save the model
and its current parameters by name model.pt.
Okay. Then I've run this for 50 epics and I can see
both the training loss and the validation loss after each epic.
We can see that both the training and
validation loss are decreasing for the first 30 or so epics.
So, the model is being saved after each of
these points where the validation loss decreases.
We can also see this decrease slowing down right around here.
In fact, our last model was saved after epic number 37.
By saving the model at the point where the validation and training loss
diverge am preventing my model from overfitting the training data,
this is also an issue of efficiency.
We should see that our validation loss stays the same for the last 10 to 15 epics here.
So, the lack of decrease here is actually indicating to
me that the best model is really reached even around epic 30,
but definitely by epic 37.
So, next step is to see how this model performs on our test data.
Here, I'm actually loading the model that we saved earlier
by name into our instantiated model,
and I'm testing it as usual.
Passing our test data into our model and recording the class accuracies.
You can see we get 97 percent overall accuracy.
This is really about the same as our last model,
the one without validation.
So, even though we train that model for 15 more epics,
the results are about the same.
This makes sense because this validation loss really isn't changing much.
So, whether we save the model after epic 37 or 50,
the model should be pretty similar.
This behavior is also occurring because most of these images are very similar.
The images are very processed and all of the digits look the same.
So, in our non validation case,
it didn't matter so much that our model trained for much longer,
but in some cases,
you will get overfitting and choosing a model
based on validation loss will be even more important.
So, model validation can be a really helpful way to
select the best model and decide when to stop training.