So far, you've learned a lot about approaching the task of image classification.
In fact, now is a good time to review the pipeline we've developed for such a task.
First, load and visualize the data you're working with,
then pre-process that data by normalizing it and converting it into a tensor,
so that it's prepped for further processing by the layers of a neural network.
Then, do your research,
has anyone approached this or similar task before?
What kind of deep learning models have already been tried and tested?
Use this research to help you decide on a model architecture and define it.
Then, decide on loss and optimization functions and proceed with training your model.
Here, you may choose to use a validation dataset
to select and save the best model during training.
Finally, test your model on previously unseen data.
At this point, feel free to take a break from what you are learning,
take time to absorb what you've learned so far.
Then when you're ready, you can keep going.
Next, I'll go over a new kind of architecture for image classification,
a convolutional neural network,
which can help us build even better image classification models.