A convolutional neural network is a special kind of
neural network in that it can remember spatial information.
The neural networks that you've seen so far only look at individual inputs.
But convolutional neural networks,
can look at an image as a whole,
or in patches and analyze groups of pixels at a time.
The key to preserving the spatial information
is something called the convolutional layer.
A convolutional layer applies a series of
different image filters also known as convolutional kernels to an input image.
The resulting filtered images have different appearances.
The filters may have extracted features like the edges of objects in that image,
or the colors that distinguish the different classes of images.
In the case of classifying digits for example,
CNN should learn to identify spatial patterns like
the curves and lines that make up the number six as distinct from another digit.
Later layers in a model will learn how to combine different color
and spatial features to produce an output like a class label.
Before we get into defining and training a complete CNN in the next couple videos,
you'll learn a bit more about the filters that define a convolutional layer.
How they're defined, and how they can transform an input image?
This will be important foundational knowledge that will come up again as you get to
training as CNN and even visualizing the inner workings of a trained CNN.