Okay. Now that you've tried to define and train a classifier of your own,
I'll show you a solution that I created.
After loading in my data and processing it,
I defined a complete CNN.
I've kept my initial convolutional layer, conv1,
that sees our input image and outputs a stack of 16 feature maps.
I'm defining all my convolutional layers first, defining two more.
Each of which doubles the depth of the output until we get to a layer with a depth of 64.
So, we're starting with an image depth of three,
then moving to 16, then 32, and finally 64.
Each of these layers uses a convolutional kernel of size three by three,
and has a padding of one.
You can also see that I've kept my one max pooling layer,
which will down-sample any XY size by two.
I've also included a dropout layer with a probability of 0.25 to prevent overfitting.
Finally, I also have a couple of fully connected layers.
This first layer will be responsible for taking as
input my final downside stack of feature maps.
I know that my original input image which is
32 by 32 by three is getting squished in the x and
y dimension and stretched in the depth dimension as it
moves through each convolutional and pooling layer.
In the forward function, you can see that I apply
a pooling layer after each convolutional layer.
So, this image will reduce in size to 16 by 16,
then eight by eight,
and finally four by four after the last pooling layer.
The third convolutional layer will have produced a depth of 64,
and that's how I get these values.
Four by four, for my final XY size,
and 64 for my depth.
That's the number of inputs that this first fully connected layer should see.
Then I'm having that produced 500 outputs.
These 500 outputs will feed as input into my final classification layer,
which will see these as inputs and produce 10 class scores as outputs.
So, let's see how all these layers are used in the forward function.
First, I'm adding a sequence of convolutional and pooling layers in sequence,
and passing our input image into our first convolutional layer,
applying an activation function than a pooling layer.
I'm doing the same thing for our second and third convolutional layers.
Finally, this resultant x,
I'm going to flatten into a vector shape.
This will allow me to pass it as input into a fully connected layer.
In between this flattening layer and each fully-connected layer,
I'm adding a dropout layer to prevent overfitting.
But then in passing my flattened image input x into my first fully connected layer.
As with all my hidden layers,
I'm applying a relu activation function.
Finally, one more dropout layer and my last fully connected layer.
The resultant x should be a list of 10 class scores.
Finally, I instantiate this model and I move it to GPU.
Below you can see that I've printed out each
of the layers in my unit function to make sure they're as I expect.
This shows me the number of inputs and outputs for each layer,
the kernel size, the stride,
and the padding, and they all checkout.
So, just to summarize, for every convolutional layer that I defined,
I apply a relu function and a max pooling layer right after that.
After that series of layers,
I flatten that representation and pass it to my fully-connected layer.
Adding some dropout, I'm finally passing it so that it produces 10 class scores.
So, I have my complete model,
and then I'm moving onto training.
I'm going to use a standard cross entropy loss,
which is useful for classification tasks like this,
and Stochastic Gradient Descent.
Then I'm actually training the network,
and I decided on training for 30 epochs.
I decided on this value after watching
the training and validation loss decrease over time.
I can see that I might have stopped training even earlier around epoch 20,
which is where the validation loss stops decreasing.
I saved my model here,
the one that got the best validation loss,
and then I loaded and tested it out.
I can see when I test this,
that I get an overall accuracy of about 70 percent.
That's not bad, it's much better than guessing for example.
If you've given this task in honest attempt,
I can say congratulations on getting this far.
You've really learned a lot about programming your own neural networks.
Of course we can see that it does better on some classes than
others and it's always interesting to think about why that might be the case.
In general, it seems like my model does better on vehicles rather than animals.
It's probably because animals really vary in color and size,
and so I might be able to improve this model if
I had more images in that particular data set.
It may also help to add another convolutional layer and see if
I could suss out more complex patterns in these images.
Here I'm just further visualizing which images it gets right or wrong.
There's plenty of room to tinker with and optimize the CNN further,
and I encourage you to do this,
it's a great learning experience.
I should mention that in 2015,
there was an online competition where
data scientists competed to classify images in this database.
The winning architecture was a CNN,
and it achieved over 95 percent test accuracy.
It took about 90 hours to train on a GPU,
which I do not encourage in this classroom.
But it does demonstrate that good accuracy is not a trivial task.