To perform image augmentation in PyTorch,
you can use the help of a built-in image transformation library.
Here you can scroll through
all the common transforms available in the transforms library.
You can see transforms that shift around the image from
left to right or that crop the image randomly.
In our case, we want our dataset to be a little more rotation and scale invariant
and so we can choose random transforms that
change the scale and how much an image is rotated.
I'm going to briefly show you how to do this in code and
then you can choose whether or not to use it in your own work.
I'm going to augment our data in the same step that I'm loading it in.
Basically, I want to add to our composite transform.
Where you've previously just seen conversion to tensors and
normalization you can put other types of transforms as well.
This transformation randomly flips an image along
its horizontal axis and this code randomly rotates an image by 10 degrees.
I apply this transform as usual when I form my training and test data.
And that's all you need to do to give your images some geometric variation.
After transforming my data,
I've gone through the same visualization steps
and we can see by looking at the borders of
some of these images that some of our images have been
rotated slightly right or left within 10 degrees.
Then to see if data augmentation actually improve the performance of
our model I use the same convolutional neural network and loop that I did before.
I trained the model over 30 epics using our augmented training data.
In this case it seemed that the training and validation mass took a little
longer to decrease but may have reached a smaller minimum.
I saved this augmented model and when I tested it,
I got one percent more accuracy in general.
This is a minor increase in test accuracy but the small performance improvements can
add up and there's something worthwhile if you're
really trying to find the best model for a task.
Generally in this course,
your job will be to design a model so that it can reach
a high accuracy but in addition to that,
choices about data augmentation and loss and
optimization functions can take that even further.
So this is a useful skill to have.