Before we move on to coding,
I should mention one more detail about the total style transfer loss.
We have values for the content and style loss,
but because they're calculated differently,
these values will be pretty different,
and we want our target image to take both into account fairly equally.
So, it's necessary to apply constant weights, alpha and beta,
to the content and style losses,
such that the total loss reflects an equal balance.
In practice, this means multiplying the style loss
by a much larger weight value than the content loss.
You'll often see this expressed as a ratio of
the content and style weights, alpha over beta.
In the paper, we see the effects of a bigger or smaller ratio.
Here is an example of a content and style image.
We can imagine that the content weight alpha is one,
and that the style weight beta is 10.
You can see that this target image is mostly content without much style,
but as beta increases to 100, then 1,000,
and alpha stays at one,
we can see more and more style in the generated image.
Finally, we see that this can go too far,
and at a ratio of 10 to the negative four,
we see that most of the content is gone,
and only style remains.
So, in general, the smaller the alpha-beta ratio,
the more stylistic effect you will see.
This makes intuitive sense because a smaller ratio
corresponds to a larger value for beta, the style weight.
You may find that certain ratios work well for one image, but not another.
These weights will be good values to change to get
the exact kind of stylized effect that you want.
All right. Now that you know the theory and math behind using
a pre-trained CNN to separate the content and style of an image,
next, you'll see how to implement style transfer in PyTorch.