So, here is a complete Gram matrix function.
This takes inner tensor which will be the output of some convolutional layer.
Then the first thing I do is take a look at its size.
Each tensor is going to be four-dimensional with a batch size,
a depth, a height, and a width.
I can ignore the batch size at this point because I'm really
interested in the depth or number of feature maps,
and the height and width.
These dimensions then tell me all I need to know to then factorize this tensor.
Next, I'm reshaping this tensor so that it's now
a 2-D shape that has its spatial dimensions flattened.
It retains the number of feature maps as the number of rows.
So, it's D rows by H times W columns.
Finally, I calculate the Gram matrix by
matrix multiplying this tensor times its transpose.
This effectively multiplies all the features and gets the correlations.
Finally, I make sure to return that calculated matrix.
Then, I can put all these pieces together,
I have my Get features function and my Gram matrix function.
Before I even start to form my target image,
I know I want to get the features from my content and style image.
Those are going to remain the same throughout this process.
So, right here I'm calling Get features on
our content image passing in our content image and the VGG model,
and I do the same thing for our style features,
passing on our style image and the VGG model.
Here, I'm calculating all the gram matrices for each of
my style layers comv 11 up to comv 51.
This looks at all of the layers in our style features and computes the gram matrix.
Then it returns a dictionary where I can call style grams
with a given layer name and get the gram matrix for that layer.
Then I'm going to create a target image.
I could start with a blank slate,
but it turns out to be easier to just start with a clone of the content image.
This way, my image will not divert too far from my octopus content and
my plan will be to iterate and change this image to stylize it more and more later.
So, in preparation for changing this target image,
I'm going to set requires-grad to true,
and I'll move it to GPU if available.
All right, the next part is the most involved part,
and next we'll talk about how to set and calculate our style and
content losses for creating interesting target images.