So in order to study the architecture of an LSTM,
let's quickly recall the architecture of an RNN.
Basically what we do is we take our event E_t and our memory M_t-1,
coming from the previous point in time,
and we apply a simple tanh or
sigmoid activation function to obtain the output and then your memory M_t.
So to be more specific,
we join these two vectors and multiply them by a matrix W and add a bias b,
and then squish this with the tanh function,
and that gives us the output M_t.
This output is a prediction and also the memory that we carry to the next node.
The LSTM architecture is very similar,
except with a lot more nodes inside and with two inputs
and outputs since it keeps track of the long- and short-term memories.
And as I said, the short-term memory is,
again, the output or prediction.
Don't get scared. These are actually not as complicated as they look.
We'll break them down in the next few videos.