So, today I'm joined by Soumith Chintala who works at Facebook AI Research,
and is the creator of PyTorch.
I want to start this interview by asking you how you got your start in AI research.
What got you interested in the field?
Sure. I always wanted to be a visual effects artist,
at least when I started my undergrad,
and then I interned at a place and they said, "You're not good enough."
No.
I was like in the art angle.
So, I was good at programming since I was a kid,
so I tried to find the next most magical thing and that was computer vision.
To me it was really compelling that you could just
magically stitch things together and your programs could understand what a code is,
what visual concepts are.
That's how I got started.
I basically tried to do stuff online,
but Udacity wasn't around back then,
so I had to find a professor in India,
which is really hard to who's doing this kind of stuff,
and there's just like one or two.
I spent six months with the professor's lab.
I started picking up some things,
then went to CMU,
tried my hand at robotics.
Then finally I landed at NYU in Yann LeCun's lab doing deep learning,
where I did ask him what are neural networks because I frankly didn't know.
Yeah, you need a place to start.
Yeah. So, that's how I got started.
What motivates me is this;
how do we make computers understand the world the way we see it?
That just seems pretty magical to me and I want to get there.
I completely agree.
So, it sounds like your journey here was an exploratory one,
would have been by curiosity and sort of having this idea of graphics in mind.
I wonder how you ended up feeling motivated to create
something like PyTorch and this kind of new usable defining framework.
Sure. Since I got to NYU,
I've been working on building up tooling for deep learning.
I worked on this project called EBLearn which was
like two generations before in terms of deep learning framework timelines.
I started there, as that was my first tool to do deep learning research.
It was very hard.
Every time we kicked off a program,
it would take 15 minutes,
and then came around Torch,
which is written by a few people who I knew.
Then I started getting pretty active and
helping people out using Torch and then delving on Torch.
That was mostly, again,
I wanted to do my research and then help other people do their research well.
At some point, we decided that we needed a new tool because as
the field moves the tools that you need to make research progress change as well.
So, you can take a tool from the 90s and say,
"Hey, I'll do my research on that",
because fundamental flexibilities, the ideas you need to express, they keep changing.
So, in end of 2016,
we decided that was the time, again,
and so I went about building PyTorch mostly because we
had a really stressful project that was really large and hard to build in Torch.
What was it that you are working on,
if you don't mind telling me?
It's around object detection.
We were trying to enter the cocoa detection challenge.
Yes.
Our network was really complicated,
it had multiple subsystems,
and it was not always differentiable.
It was this really humongous thing and Torch wasn't the right tool.
Then we briefly gave Transic a little try,
but then it didn't go with our sensibilities.
So, after that project was done,
we had some self-recollection,
and me and a couple of other people decided to just build PyTorch.
Yeah, that makes sense. I think I also find it very true where
deep learning is this dynamic field and as more tools are coming out,
you see researchers really push their limits and then ask for more and more.
Yeah.
I think that's a good way to approach designing a product with these users in mind.
So, I wanted to ask you too like removed a bit from your individual experience,
who were the first users of PyTorch and how did that
community inform how this framework evolved?
Yeah. So PyTorch had an interesting development experience.
We started with just the three of us,
and then we got other people interested within Facebook.
So, it was me, Adam Pashka,
who was an intern with me,
and Sam Gross, who's another engineer.
Were you still all working with Yann LeCun at this point?
Yeah. So, we were working at Fair and Yann LeCun Rand Fair.
It was a fairly large organization by then,
like 70, 80 people.
Fairly large fair.
Right. So, what happened was the three of us did a core iteration of the product,
saying this is how it should look.
We based off of our designs of there was a package
called Torch auto grad and like the old lower Torch.
Then there's a package called Chainer that's still around from engineers in Japan.
We thought those packages made sense,
but we also wanted the back-end of Torch,
which is really powerful.
So, combined all of that,
made something, and then we showed it to some people internally.
There's a bunch of friends internally who were
excited and wanted to contribute to the project.
Then about eight or nine people joined in part time just adding this feature,
doing things like that.
Then slowly and steadily we started giving
access to other people who I knew in the community,
the non-existent community, but I knew they were
looking for a new tool and they would like it.
So, I gave access to James Bradbury from Salesforce,
a bunch of people from the lower Torch community,
Andrej Karpathy and a few people here and there.
It would be like a review week,
we would give access to about 10 people.
Wow.
Then they would give us feedback saying, "This is broken code."
That's good feedback too.
Yeah, so we created on that for like
about six months and then in Jan we released PyTorch to the public.
That's pretty much how it all started.
The community grew.
Again, power users were our initial crowd,
and it grew from that.
It's like more completely through word of mouth.
It grew where each person tells
their friend and they switch and then the whole research labs started Torching.
It is definitely not any of the production crowd or the enterprise people,
it was more of the fun long tail of people.
Yeah, I like that.
That's how it all started.