So, you were talking about PyTorch being informed by what users are wanting,
and especially with being able to put models to production.
I was wondering if there are any other features that you hear
people clamoring for what kind of demands do you hear now,
and maybe where do you think PyTorch might move in the future?
Yes. So, one thing people do ask for on the research side is,
when they're exploring new ideas,
they don't want to be seeing like a Tenex drop in performance.
So as an example,
in PyTorch to provide an [inaudible] LSTM,
which gives you a standard LSTM,
you can configure the number of layers and what it does.
It goes really fast because it uses GPU library called cuDNN,
which was written by NVIDIA,
and so it's about 10 times faster than if you just handwrite an LSTM with four loops.
The problem that the researchers have been telling us about is that,
if they want to try some new paper idea,
this interface, the LSTM interface is very limiting,
because let's say you wanted to do something like recurrent dropout,
and [inaudible] LSTM doesn't support that,
it only supports one formulation in particular.
So, if they write it as a four loops and within LSTM cell,
they see a 10 times slow down.
I see.
So, their request recently has been, "Hey,
can we do our recurrent nets may be creative,
at the same time can get something close to cuDNN performance?"
That's an interesting request.
Again, that comes in through the GIT investment that we did.
We're trying to see if we can get users the speeds of
cuDNN by stitching high-performers GPU kernels on the fly in the backend,
based on what the users model is,
that it looks promising.
Those are requests that researchers have been asking for.
One of the things that we heard from startups,
and also people doing online courses,
they want more interactive tutorials like based on iPython Notebooks.
Also probably in embedding some digits.
They want first-class integration with Colab,
because you get free GPU [inaudible] .
That's right.
They've been asking for support for Google TPUs.
These are all the request for getting and for handling all of them.
Yes. It looks like the main cloud providers that I can
think of are happy to support the latest versions.
Yes.
PyTorch for that reason.
Yes. Amazon Azure, they made PyTorch a first-class citizen.
Google announced support not only for PyTorch being a first-class citizen,
GCP, but also they announced TPU support that we've been working with closely with them.
Yes.
Tensor Board is going to have PyTorch integration directly as well.
That's great.