So, when I think about Pitrad,
especially it'd been supportive by all these different cloud providers,
I think of it as being a separate entity from Facebook.
Which I think it definitely has its own life and community,
but I'm wondering where it fits in the larger Facebook product or if it fits at all,
where might it be used in that product?
So, Facebook has needs and the AI space.
They have Facebook AI Research and as fundamental research.
We do research in the open,
we use open datasets,
we build our research,
we publish it onto archive, to peer review.
We also have a huge set of needs for products at Facebook.
Whether it's our camera enhancements,
or whether it is our machine translation,
or whether it's our accessibility interfaces, or integrity filtering.
So, we need tools that can do all of these.
I think Facebook's investment is mostly on the perspective that if you need tools,
we are going to invest in tools anyways,
might as well make it an open-source investment.
Because Ferris mission is to do AI research in the open and advance humanity using AI.
So, this seems very,
very fitting with that mission as well.