After looking at and normalizing our image data,
we'll then create a neural network for discovering the patterns in our training data.
After training, our network should be able to look at
totally new images that it hasn't trained on,
and classify the digits contained in those images.
This previously unseen data is often called test data.
At this point, our images have been converted into vectors with 784 entries.
So, the first input layer in our MLP should have 784 nodes.
We also know that we want the output layer to distinguish
between 10 different digit types, zero through nine.
So, we'll want the last layer to have 10 nodes.
So, our model will take in a flattened image and produce 10 output values,
one for each possible class, zero through nine.
These output values are often called class scores.
A high class score indicates that a network is very
certain that a given input image falls into a certain class.
You can imagine that the class score for a 103, for example,
will have a high score for the class three and a low score for the classes zero,
one, and so on.
But it may also have a small score for
an eight or any other class that looks kind of similar in shape to a three.
The class scores are often represented as a vector of values
or even as a bar graph indicating the relative strengths of the scores.
Now, the part of this MLP architecture that's up to you to
define is really in between the input and output layers.
How many hidden layers do you want to include and how many nodes should be in each one?
This is a question you'll come across a lot as you define
neural networks to approach a variety of tasks.
I usually start by looking at any papers or
related work I can find that may act as a good guide.
In this case, I would search for MLP for MNIST,
or even more generally,
MLP for classifying small greyscale images.
Next, I'm going to ask you to perform a search like
this and see if you can find a good place to
start when it comes to defining the hidden layers of an MLP for image classification.